It's difficult to believe, but it's more
than three years since we partnered with
Shopify and start to include Shopify
connector into the business central as a
first party extension.
Since then, every release we enhanced
and improved and added something to the
connector to make sure that this
collaboration with integration is smooth
and powerful. This release is not
different. We again added more
functionality added to the two major
areas. Product information management
yeah what we are selling and the
document processing how we sell it. But
let's take a look in the details. So in
this slide you can see the list of
enhancements in the product information
uh area. But now I will walk you on
slides uh what actually has changed
this how item variant looks today. So
now we support images and we support
item attributes and these images are
also moved to the Shopify or imported
from Shopify depends on how you
configure it synchronization
and the item attributes they're not here
for decoration purposes they actually
also used in Shopify uh as a definition
of options. Yes, now you can define
which attributes will be sent to Shopify
as option. You can see in this beer
chair we can have multiple attributes
but some of them will be transferred to
the Shopify as soon as I push
information from business center. You
can see color and you can see material
descriptions and you can see images.
That's very cool. On the left side of
the Shopify admin you can see the
collections. Yeah, Shopify also have the
collections in the in their product and
there are two type of collections custom
where you as a administrator needs to
need to populate and select items to be
included into this collection or
automatic. So manual I say not with
business central. So we can import
custom collections into the business
central and decides when we export item
from business central to Shopify,
do we include it into the collection or
not or maybe multiple collections. And
with filter page, you can provide
requirements which items will be
included in which collection. For
example, I have a collections for chairs
and collection for tables and I use item
category code to distinguish which one
to use when exporting items. Look for
more information or for live demo in the
different video.
Next one. What if you manage your items
in Shopify? Or maybe you just want to
start with a business central and
migrating from a different different
product. You can get items from Shopify
with images and descriptions and then
when item is created in business central
with title,
price, cost and now with marketing text
as a description. If you're very much
creative in the marketing text and use
very interesting HTML layout, some you
might not be able to pass it through but
in general it's just there.
Another topic to discuss is Shopify
constantly enhancing the product as
well. For example, they added as a small
thing as a new type of meta field. So
you can connect
add link in the meta field of type
article which is in reality is a blog
post. So now you have the same in
business central. So the same type of
meta fields is also supported and you
can import it and do something in
business central or export. So for this
one we provided uh accessibility in our
APIs. So to make sure that you can
actually when exporting items you can
also initialize and update meta fields
as well.
The next change is interesting. Uh do
you know this setting so that actually
you are in control when you update
product information maybe pushing it
from shop from business center to
Shopify and when you update prices you
can you can have these two processes
completely isolated
for the good reason probably the the
unit cost now is a part of the price
synchronization. So it's very common
because
merchants very commonly used average uh
unit cost and they would like to see the
real cost information in the uh in the
Shopify admin as well. So with a regular
pricing even if price has not changed
the new unit cost will be sended to
Shopify and updated in the product or
variant card there.
All right.
What do we see here? We see the list of
variants and of course we see the cost
as I mentioned before uh will be updated
on regular basis but what we do not see
here and probably is a minor you do not
see here tax code the certified do not
support this field anymore so because we
update the new API we need to remove it
as well but I don't think we have any
impact on the business logic on our side
but double check with other extensions
you have on Shopify site if they use
this field somehow and uh need to find
replacement. That was uh about product
information management. Multiple
changes, all interesting ones, all
useful ones. Now to next topic,
documents, document processing. The main
theme here will be presentment currency
in sales documents. What is a
presentment currency? If you use
Shopify, you know this is a currency
used as a checkout time.
But it's not the only change. We have
other enhancement in the product and
let's like uh let's take a look at them.
Let's start with the presentment
currency. In the Shopify shop uh cart,
we have a new setting under order
processing fast which instructs business
central how you deal with the currency.
Remember in the previous series and uh
we added support for markets and market
catalogs where you can actually define
different prices for different items if
they sold in the different countries.
But it's not it. You can also define the
currency. So customer in other country
when they doing check out they can pay
in the local currency. That's convenient
for for them. They happy to pay in local
currency. That's good for your business
as well. And Shopify does the conversion
automatically. It manage the presentment
currency. It manages the uh store
currency and all of these numbers are
imported in business central. Till today
uh till the current version the created
sales document sales order or sales
invoice will be always using the store
currency the default one but now you can
decide and uh for upgraded stores you
will need to uh change this setting uh
manually and then all created documents
will have proper currency. So in in this
case you can see the Shopify order
imported and you can see that it has two
currencies. The local one uh the one
used in the transaction with the
customer apparently is Danish crowns but
also the original
amount or amount in the store currency
which is US dollars. So created document
will be created accordingly.
All right. Next one,
fulfillment. Of course, it's not enough
to import stuff. We also want to fulfill
register fulfillment information
business central and send it back. Uh
for troubleshooting purposes, we added
uh a new action so we can actually get
additional information about which
information is received together with
the fulfillment. That was probably the
last document where we forgot to add a
troubleshooting mechanism. But honestly,
it's not that uh that uh often required.
But something else has changed.
Do you know these notes? If you reading
the documentation about Shopify
connector and if you check the article
about order processing and fulfillment,
you can notice these couple of notes
describing the limitation about
fulfillment.
And I'm proud to say that we are
removing them because they're not
applicable anymore. So now uh you can
increase quantity. You can use buy X get
Y discount processes which with the same
items. You can use assemblies which are
using the oh packet bundles in Shopify
terminology which use the same item
together with the normal item sold
directly. All of them now works and uh
I'm super happy about that with a not
noticeable change but it's
great improvement from uh from quality
perspective and uh again giving you
flexibility on how to use the connector.
All right. And you can ask me what are
you showing here?
It's available field. The situation is
not all changes are driven by us.
Sometimes they driven by Shopify and
again we are uptaking the new API again
and Shopify decided to use the new field
for return uh information. We do import
it but now it's stored in the different
field. Just be aware that some changes
happened. We decided to use a new field
for this information.
All right. I mentioned updates of the
version. Exactly. In January they
release a new version which will be
valid till end of the very December
2026.
So it makes total sense to upgrade in
the April
to make sure that smooth operations till
till end of the year.
All of these changes are not actually
visible to you but uh it I think it's a
is it's a good for you to know uh what
exactly changed. So there are some
changes in how inventory availability is
processed. There are different APIs or
parameter in these APIs are used. Bulk
operations which we use for price
synchronization
and uh now product variant supports uh
2,000 variants.
So there are some uh some enhancements
in this area as well. So if you have a
huge items uh items with a lot of
variants makes sense to test. They are
now supported.
All right. You can always find just a
reminder
uh information about current version and
when it is expired in the Shopify shop
cart.
Thank you for watching. Uh there are two
more videos about the topic. You will
find the links in the descriptions about
product information management and
presentment currencies. You can also
reach out to us and our resources not
only YouTube but also link it in. And
now Viva engage which is a tool for
collaboration with partner community.
Thank you.